Wait.
잠깐만요.
&gt;&gt; What's wrong?
&gt;&gt; 무슨 일이예요?
&gt;&gt; When did this turn into a cooking show all of a sudden?
&gt;&gt; 우리, 언제부터 요리 프로그램을 하고 있는 거죠?
&gt;&gt; Since we had to talk about methods?
&gt;&gt; 메소드에 관한 얘기 할 때부터?
&gt;&gt; Care to explain, Rachael Ray?
&gt;&gt; Rachael Ray씨, 설명 좀 해주시죠?
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] Well, have you ever baked a cake before?
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] 음, 케이크 구워 본 적 있으세요?
&gt;&gt; I have eaten a cake before.
&gt;&gt; 먹어본 적이야 있죠.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; 알겠어요.
Well, then you're fully qualified for this.
그럼, 자격은 충분해요.
&gt;&gt; Okay.
&gt;&gt; 좋아요.
&gt;&gt; All you have to do to bake a cake is to put in flour, sugar.
&gt;&gt; 케이크를 구우려면 밀가루, 설탕을 넣기만 하면 되요.
&gt;&gt; The ingredients.
&gt;&gt; 재료들 말이죠.
Okay.
좋아요. &gt;&gt; 네, 재료요.
Yeah.
예.
And then you follow the instructions of the recipe.
그리고 레시피에 나온 대로 따라가는 거죠.
&gt;&gt; Okay. &gt;&gt; And then out comes a cake.
&gt;&gt; 좋아요. &gt;&gt; 그러면 케이크가 되는 거예요.
&gt;&gt; Like this?
&gt;&gt; 이렇게요?
&gt;&gt; Yeah.
&gt;&gt; 그래요.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Well
&gt;&gt; 좋아요. 음,
connect the analogy to the methods one more time.
이 비유를 메소드에 다시 한 번만 연결해 설명해 주세요.
&gt;&gt; Okay. Sure so for
&gt;&gt; 좋아요. 메소드를 만들려면
a method you can put in inputs.
입력을 해야 하잖아요.
&gt;&gt; Like we did the quantity for the display method?
&gt;&gt; 디스플레이 메소드에 수량값을 넣은 것처럼 말이죠?
&gt;&gt; Yeah, and then you execute the instructions of the method.
&gt;&gt; 그래요, 그리고 나서 메소드의 명령을 수행하는 거예요.
&gt;&gt; Okay, almost like the recipe for making a cake?
&gt;&gt; 알겠어요, 그러니까 케이크를 굽기 위한 레시피처럼 말이죠?
&gt;&gt; Mm-hm.
&gt;&gt; 으-흠.
Then you can have the output value returned.
그러면 출력이 리턴값으로 나오는 거죠.
&gt;&gt; Outputs, they are delicious.
&gt;&gt; 출력이라, 맛있네요.
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Let's look up more information
&gt;&gt; [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; 메소드에 들어가는
about input parameters for methods.
입력 파라미터에 대해 더 알아보죠.
I'm going to do a Google search for Jjava method parameter.
자바 메소드 파라미터에 대해 구글 검색을 해볼께요.
The first link looks good so I'm going to click on it.
처음 나온 링크가 괜찮아 보이네요. 클릭해보죠.
Now this article talks about passing information to a method.
이 글은 메소드에 정보를 전달하는 법에 관한 내용이군요.
Here's a code snippet that computes the monthly payments for a home loan.
여기 나온 짧은 코드는 주택 융자금 상환 월부금 계산을 하는 건데요.
It has four input parameters, loan amount, interest rate, future value
입력 파라미터가 4개 있군요. 상환금액, 이자율, 융자금 미래가치,
of the loan, as well as the number periods of the length of the loan.
그리고 융자 상환 기간 수치입니다.
And then inside this method we see that we can use these input parameters
이 메소드를 보시면 이 입력 파라미터를 변수로 사용해서
simply as variables to do our math calculations.
계산을 할 수 있음을 알 수 있습니다.
When we call the compute payment method,
상환금 계산 메소드를 호출하면,
we have to make sure we pass in the inputs in this specific order.
이 정확한 순서대로 입력해야 합니다.
So the loan amount has to go first, and then the rate and so on.
맨 처음이 상환금액이고 그 다음이 이자율, 이런 식으로 말이죠.
For the quiz in this section,
이 파트에 낸 퀴즈를 풀려면,
you'll have the chance to review this article in more detail.
이 글 전체를 자세히 읽어보시는 게 좋을 겁니다.
Within the main activity of the desk Java app,
데스크 자바 앱의 메인 액티비티 상에서,
we're going to be modifying the display quantity method and
수량 디스플레이 메소드와 입력 파라미터를 수정해서
the input parameter to give you some practice.
여러분에게 실습할 수 있는 기회를 드릴 거예요.
Notice that in the decrement method of our app,
우리 앱에서 디스플레이 수량 메소드라고 부르는 감소 메소드에선
we're passing the quantity variable over as input to this method.
입력한다는 사실을 기억하세요.
But the input parameter is called 'number', so
하지만 입력 패러미터 이름이 'number'이므로
whenever we want to refer to this input, we just have to say number.
이 입력치를 가리킬 때 역시 number라고 지칭해 주어야 합니다.
Now technically we could have used the global quantity variable within this
기술적으로는, 입력 파라미터로 전달하는 대신에
method instead of passing it as an input parameter.
이 메소드 내의 글로벌 수량 변수를 사용할 수도 있습니다.
but for the purposes of teaching you about input parameters,
하지만 여러분께 입력 파라미터에 대해 알려드리는 게 목적이기 때문에,
let's just leave it like this.
그냥 이대로 두기로 하죠.
I can change this call to the display quantity method so
이 호출문을 디스플레이 수량 메소드로 바꿔
it passes input, the number 30.
숫자 30을 입력으로 전달할 수 있습니다.
This is valid because it still matches the input data type.
입력 데이터 타입에 부합하므로 이렇게 해도 괜찮습니다.
So in the decrement method when we call it display quantity,
디스플레이 수량이라 부르는 이 감소 메소드에서는,
it will jump down here and it will execute these instructions, and
이 쪽 아래로 점프해서 이 명령들을 수행한 후에
the variable number will have the value of 30.
변수 수치가 30이 되는 것입니다.
I'll run it on my device to show you, so now when I run the minus button on my
이걸 제 기기에서 작동시켜 보여드리죠. 앱에서 마이너스 버튼을 누르면
app, it will display a quantity of 30 here.
여기에 30이라는 수량이 표시됩니다.
So let me try that.
한 번 해보죠.
There. And it actually happened like that.
여기 보이시죠. 실제로는 이렇게 해서 나오는 수치입니다.
I can also create a different variable and pass that as an input to the method.
다른 변수를 만들어서 이를 메소드에 입력할 수도 있습니다.
Here I've created a local variable called some quantity, and
여기에 some quantity라는 로컬 변수를 만들었어요. 그리고
I initialized it to 100.
100으로 초기화했습니다.
I passed this variable as input to this method,
이 변수를 메소드에 입력치로 전달했어요.
and now the number variable inside here has a value of 100.
이제 이 안에 있는 수치 변수값이 100이 되었습니다.
Let me run this on the device.
기기에서 작동해 보죠.
Now I expect when I hit the minus button the quantity will update to 100.
마이너스 버튼을 누르면 수량이 100으로 업데이트 될 겁니다.
And it does.
보시는 대로요.
These are just some things you can do to experiment with
여기 있는 것들은 입력치를 달리해서
passing in different inputs to a method.
메소드에 시험 삼아 전달해 보실 수 있어요.
As you work with input parameters,
입력 파라미터를 사용하다 보면,
another term that you might come across is arguments.
아규먼트(argument)라는 용어를 접하게 되실 겁니다.
When you call a method,
메소드를 호출할 때,
the inputs being passed to that method are called the arguments.
전달되는 입력치를 아규먼트라고 합니다.
Now this is kind of a funny word.
어찌 보면 재미있는 표현이죠.
Because when you think of arguments, you think of people yelling and
아규먼트라는 말을 생각해 보면, 사람들이 소리지르거나 서로한테
cursing at each other.
욕하는 장면이 떠오르잖아요.
But this is not like that.
하지만 여기서는 아닙니다.
Arguments are simply the inputs being passed to a method.
아규먼트란 단순히 메소드에 전달되는 입력치를 뜻하는 용어니까요.
Input parameters are the actual inputs in your method declaration and
입력 파라미터는 메소드 선언에 들어가는 실제 입력이며
those are the variables that are used within your method.
메소드 안에서 사용하는 변수입니다.
So that's a slight difference between input parameter and arguments.
따라서 입력 파라미터와 아규먼트는 약간의 차이가 있는 것이죠.
In any case, go ahead and read the article and
어쨌든 글을 계속 읽어보죠. 작성자는 여기서
the instructor notes about method parameters.
메소드 파라미터에 관해 언급하고 있는데요.
Then go ahead and experiment with the code in your app.
해당 코드를 여러분 앱으로 한번 실험해 보세요.
First try to rename the number input parameter
먼저 number라는 이름을 디스플레이 수량 메소드 선언에 있는
Just simply give it a different variable name.
변수명만 바꿔 주면 됩니다.
Then go ahead and fix any errors, and then run the app again.
그리고 에러 발생시 이를 수정하고 앱에서 작동시켜 보세요.
For the next test, go ahead and change the data type
다음 테스트는, 입력 파라미터 수치의 데이터 종류를 바꿔보는 겁니다.
of the number input parameter from an int to something else like String.
int에서 String 같이 말이죠.
Observe what happens and then go ahead and undo the change.
그러면 어떻게 되는지 확인해본 후 바꿨던 내용을 원래대로 되돌리세요.
If you want to experiment with other things, go right ahead.
다른 걸로도 시험해보고 싶으시다면 얼마든지 좋습니다.
For example, if you have a question,
예를 들어, 이러이러하게 해보면 어떻게 될지가 궁금하시다면
what would happen if I do x, then just go ahead and try it.
망설이지 말고 직접 해보세요.